<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on The Real Hathai</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/post/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on The Real Hathai</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 12:16:25 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hathai25.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Anhedonia</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/anhedonia/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 12:16:25 +0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/anhedonia/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m back&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Từng có một Manchester United như thế</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/champion.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Từng có một Manchester United như thế" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tiếng còi kết thúc trận đấu vang lên. Tỷ số:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manchester United 0 - 4 Brentford&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Đối với những ai mới chỉ bắt đầu theo dõi bóng đá vài năm gần đây, kết quả này có lẽ không còn quá xa lạ. Chương trình &amp;ldquo;Gặp nhau cuối tuần&amp;rdquo; vẫn diễn ra đều đặn ở &amp;ldquo;Nhà hát của những giấc mơ&amp;rdquo;, mang tới niềm vui và tiếng cười sảng khoái cho biết bao người trên thế giới.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuy vậy, đã từng có một Manchester United rất khác.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lịch sử thế giới ít ghi nhận những trường hợp đặc biệt như đội bóng này. Một đội bóng đã trải qua biết bao thăng trầm - từ những buổi đầu thành công cho tới ngày chuyến bay định mệnh cướp đi sinh mệnh của cả một thế hệ cầu thủ vàng của câu lạc bộ (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://vi.wikipedia.org/wiki/Th%E1%BA%A3m_h%E1%BB%8Da_h%C3%A0ng_kh%C3%B4ng_M%C3%BCnchen&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Munchen 1958&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), để rồi họ hồi sinh mạnh mẽ bằng cách lên đỉnh Châu Âu chỉ vỏn vẹn 10 năm sau đó, với đầu tàu là &lt;strong&gt;Sir Bobby Charlton&lt;/strong&gt; - kẻ sống sót vĩ đại trong chuyến bay định mệnh đó. Để rồi chính câu lạc bộ lại trải qua một chu kì đi xuống hơn chục năm, cho tới ngày &lt;strong&gt;Sir Alex Ferguson&lt;/strong&gt; tới và chắp bút cho trang sử mới của câu lạc bộ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vâng, lịch sử của United mạnh mẽ như vậy đó. Vậy nên bất chấp những năm tháng khó khăn sau khi &lt;strong&gt;Sir Alex Ferguson&lt;/strong&gt; rời chiếc ghế thuyền trưởng, mình vẫn tin ngày nào đó họ sẽ trở lại. Dẫu cho nó có hơi mù quáng, nhưng thành thật mà nói, tại sao lại không thể không yêu câu lạc bộ này được chứ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Với tất cả sự tôn trọng, mình sẽ không thể không nhắc tới &lt;strong&gt;Sir Matt Busby&lt;/strong&gt;, cùng bộ ba &lt;strong&gt;Sir Bobby Charlton, Denis Law, George Best&lt;/strong&gt; - những người làm nên đế chế Manchester United vào những năm cuối thập niên 60. Tuy vậy, phải tới khi &lt;strong&gt;Alex Ferguson&lt;/strong&gt; tới, &amp;ldquo;Quỷ đỏ&amp;rdquo; mới thực sự trở thành một biểu tượng toàn cầu, và là hình ảnh đã chiếm trọn trái tim biết bao người hâm mộ năm châu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thời gian đầu của &lt;strong&gt;Ferguson&lt;/strong&gt; chẳng dễ dàng gì. Đội trải qua bốn năm với vỏn vẹn chiếc cúp FA, thậm chí đã từng xuất hiện một biểu ngữ trên sân vào khoảng thời gian đó như sau:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Fergie - 3 năm toàn là phân&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vạn sự khởi đầu nan mà, phải không? Thật may ngày đó họ đã đặt niềm tin vào ông ấy, bởi nếu không trang sử câu lạc bộ hẳn đã mất đi một chương rất đẹp rồi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manchester United của những năm 90 là một đội bóng đẹp. Ở đó có &lt;strong&gt;Eric Cantona&lt;/strong&gt;, với chiếc cổ áo luôn để dựng - ngang tàng, ngông nghênh, nhưng thể hiện đúng cái chất của đội bóng, của chính anh khi đó: một ông vua đích thực.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/Cantona.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;1400&#34;
	height=&#34;1052&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/Cantona_hu12434490901634796925.jpeg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/Cantona_hu2941964197742592526.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Eric Cantona&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;319px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Có &lt;strong&gt;David Beckham&lt;/strong&gt;, đẹp trai, với mái tóc lãng tử, đã chinh phục biết bao chị em cũng như cầu môn với cái chân đá phạt vô cùng kì diệu. Có một câu nói cực kì nổi tiếng khẳng định đúng phẩm chất này:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/Beckham.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1600&#34;
	height=&#34;1225&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/Beckham_hu15556988396462555659.webp 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/Beckham_hu5565839770387694657.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;&amp;ldquo;Bend it like Beckham&amp;rdquo;&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;130&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;313px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rồi chúng ta có &lt;strong&gt;Paul Scholes, Ryan Giggs, hai anh em nhà Neville, Nicky Butt&lt;/strong&gt;, một thế hệ cầu thủ mà về sau được biết đến dưới cái tên: &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The class of 92&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/Classof92.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;780&#34;
	height=&#34;520&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/Classof92_hu1525040376212649440.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/Classof92_hu2707996002054268259.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Class of 92&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Và đừng quên &lt;strong&gt;Roy Keane&lt;/strong&gt; - gã điên đích thực trên sân bóng, kẻ sẵn sàng lao vào đạp chết đối phương, chiến đấu tới hơi thở cuối cùng để bảo vệ danh dự cho cái tên Manchester United.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/keano.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;956&#34;
	height=&#34;671&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/keano_hu14826288588006196272.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/keano_hu8073777937416875681.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Roy Keane chấp hết&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;142&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;341px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mình không liệt kê ra những cái tên này chỉ để khoe, bởi câu lạc bộ nào cũng có những huyền thoại. Nhưng điều làm nên Manchester United chính là những câu chuyện của họ - những câu chuyện đầy cảm xúc, thứ mà người ta mong chờ nhất ở một trận đấu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quay trở lại với &lt;strong&gt;Cantona&lt;/strong&gt;: bạn có biết người được coi là biểu tượng của câu lạc bộ đã từng bay vào đám đông cổ động viên đội bạn để tặng cho tên khốn đó &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/C7PSY7KYThk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;một cú cước&lt;/a&gt; vì bị hắn xúc phạm? Mãi về sau này, khi được phỏng vấn về sự cố đó, Cantona vẫn thản nhiên trả lời: &amp;ldquo;ngày đó nếu chọn lại, đáng ra tôi phải đạp thằng đấy mạnh hơn nữa&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hay là với &lt;strong&gt;Beckham&lt;/strong&gt; - bộ mặt của United, nhưng chính gương mặt điển trai đó từng ăn trọn &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/9dCixiClxBI&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;cái giày&lt;/a&gt; của &lt;strong&gt;Ferguson&lt;/strong&gt; sau một trận đấu tệ hại, bởi khi đó vị cha già cho rằng &lt;strong&gt;Beckham&lt;/strong&gt; đã quá mải mê vào những công chuyện của showbiz kể từ ngày quen &lt;strong&gt;Victoria&lt;/strong&gt;, để rồi phải cuốn gói rời khỏi United ngay mùa sau đó.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bạn không thể tìm những mẩu tin như thế ở một câu lạc bộ khác. Và nhắc tới Manchester United thì còn có một điều không thể không đề cập: những cú lội ngược dòng.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Như mình nói ở trên, thể thao là một hình thức giải trí, và mục đích cuối cùng của nó là mang lại cảm xúc, dư vị cho người xem. Nếu bạn là người Việt Nam, chắc chắn bạn đã từng trải nghiệm điều đó vào mùa xuân 2018 cùng U23 Vietnam. Thật tệ khi cứ phải thấp thỏm lo lắng, nhưng rồi được vỡ òa ở những giây phút cuối cùng có tuyệt hơn không? Điều đó giống như về lý chúng ta cần chọn một người ổn định, nhưng không thể không bị cuốn hút bởi những người mang lại cho bản thân nhiều cảm xúc hơn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manchester United là như thế.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dù cho tỉ số có là đang bị dẫn trước 0-2, 0-3, và trận đấu còn 15 phút. Bạn sẽ bắt đầu thấy &lt;strong&gt;Ferguson&lt;/strong&gt; đứng ngoài đường biên, mắt dõi theo, thỉnh thoảng giơ cao đôi tay chỉ vào chiếc đồng hồ, miệng chóp chép miếng kẹo cao su. Trước khi người ta kịp phân tích những cử chỉ đó của &lt;strong&gt;Ferguson&lt;/strong&gt;, United đã thắng chung cuộc 3-2. Thậm chí là 4-3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Họ gọi đó là &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fergie Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Không có một nghiên cứu nào có thể lí giải hiện tượng kì bí này. Cổ động viên chỉ biết trầm trồ, thán phục, sau mỗi lần &amp;ldquo;Quỷ đỏ&amp;rdquo; lội ngược dòng, dẫu cho thời lượng trận đấu chỉ còn được tính bằng giây.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rốt cuộc họ làm điều đó kiểu gì vậy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Năm 1999 là năm đầu tiên cúp C1 được phát sóng trên lãnh thổ Việt Nam. Có lẽ những người chú, người bác mình đã từng chọn Manchester United để mến mộ sau &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/LC_f9CB1Pmg&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;khoảnh khắc này&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/ole.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;800&#34;
	height=&#34;600&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/ole_hu10610019119159596118.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/ole_hu9211563529409106541.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Bàn thắng ở phút cuối cùng của Solskjaer giúp Man.United lội ngược dòng lên ngôi vô địch cúp Châu Âu&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thứ mà Manchester United mang lại đơn thuần là cảm xúc. Nhưng bạn có thể tìm được thứ cảm xúc này nhiều đến vậy ở câu lạc bộ nào trong làng túc cầu ngoài họ chứ? Khoảng thời gian 2000-2010 chứng kiến một Manchester United trình làng một thế hệ mới với những &lt;strong&gt;Ronaldo, Rooney, Ferdinand, Vidic, Van de Sar,&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt; để rồi họ một lần nữa &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/WdBAoWUQDhI&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;lên đỉnh Châu Âu&lt;/a&gt; theo cái cách không thể Manchester United hơn - trên chấm Penalty đầy may rủi. Cầu thủ xuất sắc nhất mùa đó, quả bóng vàng thế giới 2008 - &lt;strong&gt;Ronaldo&lt;/strong&gt; - là người duy nhất sút trượt bên phía Manchester United (ai mà ngờ tới chứ). Tưởng như mọi chuyện đã kết thúc, nhưng không.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/terry.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1000&#34;
	height=&#34;580&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/terry_hu16380538928958163034.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/terry_hu7838464459113234704.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Cú trượt chân của Terry, gián tiếp dâng chức vô địch cho Manchester United&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;172&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;413px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thực sự thì định mệnh đã chọn Mancheter United vào đêm Moskow huyền ảo. Bạn không tin ư? Vậy giải thích cho mình việc tại sao trong cú đá quyết định, người đội trưởng của Chelsea phải trượt chân, và bóng phải đi trúng cột dọc?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manchester United là như thế, luôn chiến thắng theo cách cảm xúc nhất có thể.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Những hồi ức về đội bóng, dẫu cho là khoảnh khắc vinh quang hay nỗi buồn khi thất bại, mình sẽ chẳng thể nào quên, dù cho phần lớn lịch sử đó mình đã không được trực tiếp dõi theo. Đó thực sự là những trang sử có thể khiến cho người ta phải nổi da gà mỗi khi nghĩ về. Đó cũng là lí do mà mình yêu đội bóng này, bởi kể cả khi không chiến thắng, họ cũng thất bại đầy cảm xúc. Một đội bóng vĩ đại, cùng những cái tôi vĩ đại, đầy cá tính, làm sao có thể không yêu?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Có lẽ để tổng kết lại về Manchester United trong một bức hình, đối với mình chính là khoảnh khắc &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtu.be/JpyJtjLoDKg&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;này&lt;/a&gt; (bấm vào hình để gif chạy nhé!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/cantona.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;480&#34;
	height=&#34;480&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/cantona_hu4696145047115121952.gif 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/t%E1%BB%ABng-c%C3%B3-m%E1%BB%99t-manchester-united-nh%C6%B0-th%E1%BA%BF/cantona_hu6192836826601300793.gif 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Khoảnh khắc Cantona ăn mừng sau pha ghi bàn vào lưới Sunderland - 1996&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;100&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;240px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bạn thấy chứ? Ngang tàng, đầy khí phách, dẫu đang thắng hay thua, &lt;strong&gt;Cantona&lt;/strong&gt; và Manchester United luôn ngẩng cao đầu, với chiếc cổ áo dựng lên khinh đời - một vị vua đích thực. &lt;strong&gt;Cantona&lt;/strong&gt; vẫn sẽ mãi là &lt;strong&gt;Cantona&lt;/strong&gt;, bởi đó là con quỷ đỏ mang trong mình tinh thần United đích thực.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chỉ tiếc có lẽ, từ sau khi &lt;strong&gt;Ferguson&lt;/strong&gt; nghỉ hưu, tinh thần đó đã theo ông rời khỏi sân &lt;strong&gt;Old Trafford&lt;/strong&gt; rồi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Eminem spirit</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/the-eminem-spirit/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/the-eminem-spirit/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/the-eminem-spirit/img.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post The Eminem spirit" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been questioning my motivation. It feels like I have no reason to continue everything I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. I always feel sleepy. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t concentrate on my work, and my study, even though I was having my semester final exam. It was also the reason why I didn&amp;rsquo;t post anything on this blog for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, just when I find myself at the lowest, something comes back to me. Do you know what it is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening to Eminem&amp;rsquo;s music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I found out about his music. It was 6 years ago, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not Afraid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was immediately drawn to his lyrics and flows. At that time I didn&amp;rsquo;t know rap or hip hop, but I think he was speaking some emotional, inspiring thing that a student - in a teenage year like me - really needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, when you were 14 - 15, you started to grow older, and have your thoughts about life. You have some weird illusion about yourself and think that no one can understand you. My mom calls that age &amp;ldquo;the stupidest time in a human&amp;rsquo;s life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t have many friends back then. My day would only be like this: wake up, go to school, study, go home, games, sleep, and so on. Meanwhile, kids my age would hang out with each other all the time, eat out, go to the movies, etc. Basically I was a nerd, so my friends don&amp;rsquo;t want to play with me. You need to be &amp;ldquo;cool&amp;rdquo; to play with many people at secondary school, you know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, everything&amp;rsquo;s changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yeah&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a ride&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I guess I had to go to that place&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To get to this one&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now some of you might still be in that place&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re tryna get out&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just follow me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll get you there&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are the beginning lines of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not Afraid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.
Goosebumps, huh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His music has taught me so many things in life. I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to build trust in myself, overcome my shyness, always stand tall, and not give up. The day I took my high school entrance exam, I listened to Lose Yourself right before I entered the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music can make a different impact on each person. Although his music was controversial, I find it relatable and use his lyrics as my energy whenever I&amp;rsquo;m down for mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got into college, I listened to his music less. Partially because I got busier, but also because I got attracted to many other things. Trust me, when you&amp;rsquo;re in your 20s, it&amp;rsquo;s hard not to be attracted to some crazy things youth this age can do. Here are a few examples: spending money on unhealthy food, trips, clothes, etc. Of course not everything&amp;rsquo;s bad, but when people started to look at you differently, you have more things to concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence my GPA dropped. It&amp;rsquo;s not that bad, but it&amp;rsquo;s not what I expected at the beginning of this semester. I know I can achieve more, but I was so lazy and eventually got what I deserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i0EA3ur5mj4&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Stupid Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is my video that I make subtitles for one of Eminem&amp;rsquo;s songs. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I even made it but thank God, I feel like that same old energy was coming back to me. Just like 6 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Eminem spirit - not giving up, not giving a fuck about shit, only focus on what matters to you the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a long-lost spirit. Hope it&amp;rsquo;ll stay for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A day at Fville!</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/fpt.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A day at Fville!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got a chance to visit Fville - an FPT Software campus - yesterday. It was an amazing trip, with many exciting experiences and provoking thoughts for me. Before talking about what I think, let&amp;rsquo;s revisit the campus with me, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-experiences&#34;&gt;My experiences
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The journey began at 12:10 pm. We got picked up by a bus at our school library and head our way straight to Hoa Lac Hi-tech Park, which is about 40km far from my university (you can see the direction below). It took us 50 minutes to get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/map.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/map_hu4191623513522416740.png 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/map_hu16991177572093314178.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know, FPT Software is part of the FPT Corporation - one of the largest groups in Vietnam. This trip was held for students in HUST (like me) to see the chance of internships and working at FPT Software. Fville is one of FPT Software&amp;rsquo;s campuses, a space where its employees work together and enjoy all the facilities that suit their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, back to the story! When we arrived at the Fville, I was stunned by the view of the space. Fville has a modern design and is surrounded by &amp;ldquo;green&amp;rdquo; elements - trees, lakes, and grass paths. They even built a dam around the whole site to bring cool air into the buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/img.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2560&#34;
	height=&#34;1920&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/img_hu14853758836190081162.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/img_hu10741985886582225782.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;View from the lobby&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They give names for each floor and part of each floor following the name of streets in Hanoi. If I remember right, the first floor is called &amp;ldquo;Future&amp;rdquo;, with Ba Dinh &amp;amp; Hoan Kiem districts (2 districts of Hanoi), and each room will be named after a street or a lake. They have a map that includes everything about the area, but I forgot to take picture of that (my bad).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went into a big hall, called &amp;ldquo;Chu Sau&amp;rdquo; (Uncle Six?). They welcomed us with a small presentation about FPT, its history, and the corporate culture. After that, we played a small Kahoot about everything we just listened to, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t win it (I hate Kahoot). Next, they split us into groups to play a small game. The game required each team to solve a passcode. Our team solved the passcode shortly, and we found out our objective was to take a picture at the reception desk - which they use to upload on their FB fan page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the game is over, we could finally start to visit the building. Our tour guide was an FPT TA (talent acquisition) and an undergraduate student of FPT University. They were both kind, friendly, and energetic (also pretty :&amp;gt;). We got to see the facilities of Fville: gym, billiard, canteen, pool, working space (looks like they come here just to chill &amp;hellip;). They even have a motel that their employee can hire with a maximum of five people/ room for only 100k VND (which means less than a cup of coffee for each?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/lake.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2568&#34;
	height=&#34;1926&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/lake_hu543771999105064678.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/lake_hu6796744678804331068.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;My team in the middle of the lake&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/cuder.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2568&#34;
	height=&#34;1926&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/cuder_hu16333534971581016196.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/cuder_hu8766553038437069847.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;With the CUDER statue&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I like is that they have buses to pick their employees to work and give them catering services, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about how to get there, or buying food on the way home. It&amp;rsquo;s super convenient!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then return to the hall (&amp;ldquo;Chu Sau&amp;rdquo;) to play some team-building games. Our team got 4th out of 6 teams, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, because we had a wonderful time together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/final.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2493&#34;
	height=&#34;1869&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/final_hu15535054423945946303.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/final_hu8569683201191455674.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;After the bonding game&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-thoughts&#34;&gt;My thoughts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After spending the afternoon there, having the chance to meet new people and see new things, I think I have learned so many things. Despite being a second-year student, I still struggle to find my path for my career, whether to become a developer to work in software or blockchains, or becoming an IoT engineer, or work at low-code positions like BA, QA, QC, DevOps, or maybe even work in HR, I still don&amp;rsquo;t know. But after the trip, I think I got my answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just do your thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, just do your thing. Focus on it and let it guide you. Many of the employees I met yesterday didn&amp;rsquo;t take the job that they learned at the university, but they all seemed happy with their job (at least that&amp;rsquo;s what I thought).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I mean is, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry that much about what to do in the future. If you have something that you&amp;rsquo;ve already worked on, keep doing it, and be good at it. That thing will lead you to opportunities that you might never think about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust me, I&amp;rsquo;m speaking from my own experience. Last year I held a &lt;strong&gt;TEDx Conference&lt;/strong&gt; - many ITers considered that a waste of time - but that experience has taught me so many things, and offer me the chance to work and make connections with people, which brought opportunities for me later on. My tour guide at FPT studied at &lt;strong&gt;FTU&lt;/strong&gt; (Foreign Trade University), a university that has nothing to do with technology, but many of her friends are working as Bridge Engineer and DevOps (which required knowledge in IT). And you know what they all have in common?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They ALL didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to do in their junior years, nor intended to do this job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of them got this position because they joined a club at university and worked on events, and one of them happened to be an event held by FPT. They took their chance to get their internship at FPT through that, and found out their exceptional skills would be suitable to be a DevOps. Do you get what I mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right people will come to you at the right time, just when you&amp;rsquo;re doing things you feel right. Don&amp;rsquo;t compare yourself to others, because you&amp;rsquo;ve already known:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re just doing their things.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Reminiscence</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/reminiscence/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/reminiscence/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/reminiscence/img.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Reminiscence" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A day can be special in many ways. So does the 9th of May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started at the beginning of 2018. The year that my life completely changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four years ago, someone stepped into my life. Someone used to be dreamy and mournful at the same time. Someone added laughter and tears to my daily days, emotions, and things that you could never forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone said yes on this day. Someone received a ring on this day, even though it didn&amp;rsquo;t fit at first. Someone tore me apart on this day, right before many decisive exams - I can still remember I was crying while doing that Toeic test. Someone came back, also on this day, after leaving for half a year, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t stay till the same day four years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where did we go wrong?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not someone&amp;rsquo;s fault, it&amp;rsquo;s just life separates us into different paths. You couldn&amp;rsquo;t chase after your dream and become a person I&amp;rsquo;ve never known. I achieved more than I can ever think of and become a person I&amp;rsquo;ve never expected. We both have gone so far from our path, increasing the distance between us. Do you think so?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if those years are enough for a lifetime. It&amp;rsquo;s stupid thinking so, but when I try to be in a new relationship or intend to, I just feel like trying to repeat everything in the past. Maybe I let others down, but what can I say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not trying to be nostalgic or missing someone. In the end, the memories stay, they might haunt you for days and nights, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got over that time. Now I can sit back and be calmful recalling everything, with a smile and pity on my face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey, what a love story that was!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ever come across this, just know that I cherish all the things we&amp;rsquo;ve been through. All the good and bad memories, all took part in making me who I am today. Maybe one day when everything is long gone, we&amp;rsquo;ll meet again, but as a different, grown person, with all the memories left behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whatever happened, you and I, we both deserve to be appreciated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Dawn Ahead</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/img.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Dawn Ahead" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s May. Summer is coming, with plenty of work ahead for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I have some projects to finish. One is from my club, which is to make some kinda blog website. One is from my class, in which I have to develop software to illustrate some sorting algorithms. Both are pretty challenging and even though I&amp;rsquo;ve been really familiar with such projects, they&amp;rsquo;ll still take me lots of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I&amp;rsquo;m competing in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creative Idea Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; at my university - a contest for students to present their startup ideas. If I can make it through the final round, I can present my idea in front of many people in English at the &lt;strong&gt;B1 lecture hall&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be a big day, and I really look forward to that, since that hall is incredibly cool, you can see it below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/hall.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1000&#34;
	height=&#34;667&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/hall_hu13877935389212698426.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/hall_hu3265428653450839009.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;149&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;359px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I&amp;rsquo;m having my mid-term exams at the end of the month,  just in time the above contest is over. This semester I&amp;rsquo;m studying &lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; subjects, which is an insane number (at least to me). But I&amp;rsquo;m not afraid. I will never give up once I&amp;rsquo;ve set the goals for myself, so let&amp;rsquo;s see how far I can go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny how terrible and stress I was last week and now I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get through everything. Today is labour day, and I think I can really sit back, chill out, enjoy the air of my countryside, as I can hardly have the chance to feel it once more the following month. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it peaceful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/sunset.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2559&#34;
	height=&#34;2560&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/sunset_hu5761924745262795251.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/sunset_hu8924083137063587004.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The title is dawn, but this picture is the sunset =))&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;99&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;239px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here.we.go!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Gloomy Sunday</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/gloomy-sunday/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/gloomy-sunday/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/gloomy-sunday/img.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Gloomy Sunday" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Sunday, the end of the week. Time to go out, refresh, and have yourself some rest after a long, tiring week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first month of my new semester has passed. I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to study quite hard this semester, and everything seems overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two homework this weekend, and both of them are from my coding classes. One is OOP, and the other one is the Programming Technique. Somehow I still haven&amp;rsquo;t finished both. It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating, especially when doubt starts to creep into your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many times have I wondered whether I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen the right major to study or not? I&amp;rsquo;m not a bad student at school, and I can proudly say I belong to the top ones. I know my strength compared to other students and the admiration I get from people. I know all of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why do I still feel so empty every Sunday?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People said I should be proud and satisfied with everything I&amp;rsquo;ve got. They think that I&amp;rsquo;m confident, sociable, and extremely good at my major. I even have a better income than most of the students my age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only if they knew how much I have sacrificed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned earlier, my two homework has caused me to doubt myself. It&amp;rsquo;s harmful to your mental health, especially when you&amp;rsquo;ve always tried so hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not intelligent. Not at all. Everything I&amp;rsquo;ve got was through trial and error. I hate when people say I&amp;rsquo;m smart, I&amp;rsquo;ll know how to resolve my own problem eventually. Or when they say I&amp;rsquo;m always confident and able to speak freely and get everyone&amp;rsquo;s attention. They don&amp;rsquo;t know my heart always beats like a drum while my body shakes every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why I always have an unconfident feeling whenever I tackle a difficult problem or situation. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I&amp;rsquo;m reaching my limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s even worse when there&amp;rsquo;s no one there for you to share your thoughts. I have friends, and many of them can really lend me an ear, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard for them to understand me thoroughly. They don&amp;rsquo;t know this side of me, partly because I hardly show it, partly because we&amp;rsquo;re basically not in the same league. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying this to dignify myself, but when you&amp;rsquo;re better than people, you&amp;rsquo;ll always feel lonely because they won&amp;rsquo;t ever know how to become someone like you, to feel the way you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, it will be just me and myself. I wish there could be someone else here, but that&amp;rsquo;s the price I have to pay. Maybe one day I&amp;rsquo;ll be rewarded. One day&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then, I still need to be strong. I might have a bad day like today, but I know I&amp;rsquo;ll come back stronger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get yourself up, as a new week is coming.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>UML: Use Case Diagram Tutorial</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/background.jpg" alt="Featured image of post UML: Use Case Diagram Tutorial" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I want to talk about &lt;em&gt;Use case Diagram&lt;/em&gt;, one of the basic knowledge you need to know when studying Object-oriented Programming (OOP). For the illustrations in this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;em&gt;Astah UML&lt;/em&gt;, a design tool that supports UML. You can download it &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://astah.net/downloads/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and learn how to use it with this &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://astah.net/support/astah-pro/user-guide/usecase-diagram/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-use-case-diagram&#34;&gt;What is a use case diagram?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Object-oriented paradigm, when it comes to designing the system, we often demonstrate that by the Unified Modeling Language (UML). A use case diagram can be used to summarize the details of your system&amp;rsquo;s users and their interaction with the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what exactly is the user&amp;rsquo;s interaction with the system?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good question. Supposed that you&amp;rsquo;re building an application, let&amp;rsquo;s say an online Bookstore. In this case, &lt;strong&gt;interactions&lt;/strong&gt; are the things users can do with your application, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viewing books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buying books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding books to cart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add as many interactions as you can think of, but you got the point. And we can demonstrate the user&amp;rsquo;s interaction through the &lt;em&gt;Use case Diagram&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s learn how to draw it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-case-diagram-components&#34;&gt;Use case diagram components
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are 5 main components you&amp;rsquo;ll be working with in a use case diagram:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Association&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;System Boundary Box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relationships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;actor&#34;&gt;Actor
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An actor is a user that interacts with the system. It can be a person, an organization, or even a server/ system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to identify the actor, you need to answer this very basic question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Who will &lt;strong&gt;interact&lt;/strong&gt; with the application?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say you need to build an e-commerce website. So who will be the actor here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty simple, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a use case diagram, an actor is normally drawn as a stickman, but it can also be drawn as in the picture below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/actor.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;676&#34;
	height=&#34;308&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/actor_hu12378382425589067789.webp 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/actor_hu807673484268472788.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Actor in Use case diagram&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;219&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;526px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can draw the actor at your will, as long as there&amp;rsquo;s a detailed name with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;use-case-association--boundary&#34;&gt;Use case, Association &amp;amp; Boundary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;These definitions are pretty straightforward, so I&amp;rsquo;ll just give you the concept and their symbols in the use case diagram:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use cases&lt;/strong&gt;: Horizontally shaped ovals that represent the different uses that a user might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Association&lt;/strong&gt;: A line between actors and use cases. In complex diagrams, it is important to know which actors are associated with which use cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System boundary boxes&lt;/strong&gt;: A box that sets a system scope to use cases. All use cases outside the box would be considered outside the scope of that system. For example: In a bank, a client can only view their transactions, not all the transactions in the system, since that &lt;em&gt;use case&lt;/em&gt; is out of their scope.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to work with the above components, since they&amp;rsquo;re not hard to understand. The thing that might actually confuse you is &lt;strong&gt;Relationships&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;relationships&#34;&gt;Relationships
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are 3 types of relationships:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complicated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip; Wait, wrong topic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 3 types of relationships, again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generalization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;include&#34;&gt;Include
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Include is like a must-have relationship between use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about include this way: suppose you&amp;rsquo;re hungry and want to get something to eat. You walk into MacDonald&amp;rsquo;s and say: &amp;ldquo;I want to order food!&amp;rdquo;. But what do you have to do first before that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have to choose what to eat first!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you can draw it in your use case diagram like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/include.png&#34;
	width=&#34;836&#34;
	height=&#34;552&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/include_hu14555247635961733947.png 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/include_hu3944489149254116599.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;151&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;363px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to order food, you need to choose what to buy, pretty reasonable, right? That is the &lt;em&gt;include&lt;/em&gt; relationship. Only when you finish choosing can you proceed to the payment. I&amp;rsquo;ve added another include use case to our diagram, &amp;ldquo;Pay the food&amp;rdquo; for later use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s move on to the next one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;extend&#34;&gt;Extend
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I said earlier, include is a must-have relationship between use cases. However, extend is optional. That means if a use case is not compulsory, the actor can choose whether to do it, then it&amp;rsquo;s an extend relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if we go back to our previous example, the MacDonald&amp;rsquo;s one. When you pay for your food, it&amp;rsquo;s optional that you tip the waiter. We can demonstrate that in our use case diagram like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/extend.png&#34;
	width=&#34;957&#34;
	height=&#34;717&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/extend_hu7962221294301861027.png 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/extend_hu13708238270058146818.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, pretty straightforward. When it comes to relationships in the use case diagram, just remember: Include is compulsory, extend is optional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;generalization&#34;&gt;Generalization
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Generalization is basically to show a parent-child relationship between use cases or even actors. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some use cases generalization relationships:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login (parent) -&amp;gt; Login with phone/ email (Child)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay (parent) -&amp;gt; Pay with Paypal/ COD (Child)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actors generalization relationships:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manager -&amp;gt; Staff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wholesalers -&amp;gt; Retailers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will use our MacDonald&amp;rsquo;s example here again to demonstrate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/generalization.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1170&#34;
	height=&#34;550&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/generalization_hu12371285201575097771.png 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/generalization_hu676996171958288837.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;212&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;510px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, generalization helps you display your use case diagram more clearer. If you learned Object-oriented programming (OOP), you&amp;rsquo;d realize that generalization is inheritable (Inheritance in OOP), which means the child inherits the parent&amp;rsquo;s properties and relationships of other use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everything I just went through above is just the basics of the use case diagram. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, there&amp;rsquo;s always more to learn, but I think that&amp;rsquo;s enough to draw your OOP assignments at school. Speaking of which, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll end the tutorial by showing you my very first use case diagram (I literally studied how to draw it for 10 mins because I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize that assignment&amp;rsquo;s deadline was in 1 hour). See you around!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/firstDiagram.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1645&#34;
	height=&#34;982&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/firstDiagram_hu1917597273732658407.png 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/uml-use-case-diagram-tutorial/firstDiagram_hu15178943850780699027.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Dumb diagram&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;167&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;402px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Oh my gosh it&amp;rsquo;s so terrible and faulty..)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A Letter To Myself</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-letter-to-myself/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-letter-to-myself/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-letter-to-myself/img.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A Letter To Myself" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You wake up. Sun is shining, birds are singing, got yourself a hot coffee and you look outside the window to watch the sunrise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a wonderful start to the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, did you forget something? Today&amp;rsquo;s the final exam day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nah, you didn&amp;rsquo;t forget that. In fact, you knew it was coming, like, a month ago. Yeah, a month ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One month ago, you got all your exam schedules. You had prepared and listed out everything you need to do to prepare for all those exams, so no big deal! Everything would be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three weeks ago, your friend told you about a contest, which you found interesting. Or maybe you didn&amp;rsquo;t think it was that interesting, you just FOMO that you might lose the chance while everyone else didn&amp;rsquo;t. You spent a day just considering that, and in the end, you say no. But you lost a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, you were assigned a new task. It&amp;rsquo;s a new and challenging one since you&amp;rsquo;ve never worked on such projects before. At this time, you&amp;rsquo;ve finished some subjects&amp;rsquo; tests, and you had barely studied for the last one, the one that would come today. But still, that task was so intriguing, you decided to take that anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One week ago, you were still working on that project, at the same time studying for the final subject. You&amp;rsquo;re completely stressed out and exhausted. But more and more works kept on coming, just like Murphy&amp;rsquo;s law:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Anything that can go wrong will go wrong.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You started to feel hopeless. Three days to the exam, you had only studied half the subject.&lt;br&gt;
Two days to the exam, still no progress. One day to the exam&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiktok, tiktok. Time still ticking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day to the exam. You felt hopeless. How come everything always has to come at once?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s not something new these days. I mean, we all have plenty of work to do. Some we can control. Some we can&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hey, things still need to be done. It&amp;rsquo;s our responsibility to do that. We can&amp;rsquo;t control what&amp;rsquo;s coming to us, but we can control our emotions and act. How you face challenges, how you solve them, you&amp;rsquo;re the one who decides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to not be okay. But promise me, you&amp;rsquo;ll be strong afterward. Take a step back, like get some sleep, and return stronger than ever. Promise me you won&amp;rsquo;t give up, because you&amp;rsquo;ve tried so hard to go this far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better days will come, I promise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Markdown Syntax Guide</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/markdown-syntax-guide/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/markdown-syntax-guide/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/markdown-syntax-guide/pawel-czerwinski-8uZPynIu-rQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Markdown Syntax Guide" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;headings&#34;&gt;Headings
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following HTML &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;—&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;h6&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; elements represent six levels of section headings. &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is the highest section level while &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;h6&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is the lowest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;h1&#34;&gt;H1
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;h2&#34;&gt;H2
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;h3&#34;&gt;H3
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;h4&#34;&gt;H4
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;h5&#34;&gt;H5
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;h6 id=&#34;h6&#34;&gt;H6
&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;Paragraph
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Xerum, quo qui aut unt expliquam qui dolut labo. Aque venitatiusda cum, voluptionse latur sitiae dolessi aut parist aut dollo enim qui voluptate ma dolestendit peritin re plis aut quas inctum laceat est volestemque commosa as cus endigna tectur, offic to cor sequas etum rerum idem sintibus eiur? Quianimin porecus evelectur, cum que nis nust voloribus ratem aut omnimi, sitatur? Quiatem. Nam, omnis sum am facea corem alique molestrunt et eos evelece arcillit ut aut eos eos nus, sin conecerem erum fuga. Ri oditatquam, ad quibus unda veliamenimin cusam et facea ipsamus es exerum sitate dolores editium rerore eost, temped molorro ratiae volorro te reribus dolorer sperchicium faceata tiustia prat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Itatur? Quiatae cullecum rem ent aut odis in re eossequodi nonsequ idebis ne sapicia is sinveli squiatum, core et que aut hariosam ex eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;blockquotes&#34;&gt;Blockquotes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The blockquote element represents content that is quoted from another source, optionally with a citation which must be within a &lt;code&gt;footer&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;cite&lt;/code&gt; element, and optionally with in-line changes such as annotations and abbreviations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;blockquote-without-attribution&#34;&gt;Blockquote without attribution
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiam, ad mint andaepu dandae nostion secatur sequo quae.
&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; that you can use &lt;em&gt;Markdown syntax&lt;/em&gt; within a blockquote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;blockquote-with-attribution&#34;&gt;Blockquote with attribution
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t communicate by sharing memory, share memory by communicating.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
— &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Rob Pike&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tables&#34;&gt;Tables
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tables aren&amp;rsquo;t part of the core Markdown spec, but Hugo supports supports them out-of-the-box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Age&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Bob&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;27&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Alice&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;23&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;inline-markdown-within-tables&#34;&gt;Inline Markdown within tables
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Italics&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Bold&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;italics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;code&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;A&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;B&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;C&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;D&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;E&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;F&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit.&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Phasellus ultricies, sapien non euismod aliquam, dui ligula tincidunt odio, at accumsan nulla sapien eget ex.&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Proin eleifend dictum ipsum, non euismod ipsum pulvinar et. Vivamus sollicitudin, quam in pulvinar aliquam, metus elit pretium purus&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Proin sit amet velit nec enim imperdiet vehicula.&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Ut bibendum vestibulum quam, eu egestas turpis gravida nec&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Sed scelerisque nec turpis vel viverra. Vivamus vitae pretium sapien&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-blocks&#34;&gt;Code Blocks
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;code-block-with-backticks&#34;&gt;Code block with backticks
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 6
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 7
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 8
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 9
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;10
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34; data-lang=&#34;html&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;!doctype html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;lang&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;en&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;charset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;utf-8&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Example HTML5 Document&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Test&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;code-block-indented-with-four-spaces&#34;&gt;Code block indented with four spaces
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!doctype html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Example HTML5 Document&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Test&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;code-block-with-hugos-internal-highlight-shortcode&#34;&gt;Code block with Hugo&amp;rsquo;s internal highlight shortcode
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 6
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 7
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 8
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 9
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;10
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34; data-lang=&#34;html&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;!doctype html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;lang&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;en&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;charset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;utf-8&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Example HTML5 Document&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Test&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;diff-code-block&#34;&gt;Diff code block
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-diff&#34; data-lang=&#34;diff&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;[dependencies.bevy]
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git = &amp;#34;https://github.com/bevyengine/bevy&amp;#34;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;rev = &amp;#34;11f52b8c72fc3a568e8bb4a4cd1f3eb025ac2e13&amp;#34;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;gd&#34;&gt;- features = [&amp;#34;dynamic&amp;#34;]
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;gd&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;gi&#34;&gt;+ features = [&amp;#34;jpeg&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;dynamic&amp;#34;]
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;list-types&#34;&gt;List Types
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;ordered-list&#34;&gt;Ordered List
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;unordered-list&#34;&gt;Unordered List
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And another item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;nested-list&#34;&gt;Nested list
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fruit
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Banana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dairy
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-elements--abbr-sub-sup-kbd-mark&#34;&gt;Other Elements — abbr, sub, sup, kbd, mark
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;GIF&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; is a bitmap image format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;2&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;O&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;X&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;n&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; + Y&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;n&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; = Z&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;n&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;CTRL&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;+&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;ALT&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;+&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Delete&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; to end the session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;salamanders&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; are nocturnal, and hunt for insects, worms, and other small creatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hyperlinked-image&#34;&gt;Hyperlinked image
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://google.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.google.com/images/branding/googlelogo/1x/googlelogo_light_color_272x92dp.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Google&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above quote is excerpted from Rob Pike&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PAAkCSZUG1c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; during Gopherfest, November 18, 2015.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
