<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Blog on The Real Hathai</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/categories/blog/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Blog on The Real Hathai</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hathai25.github.io/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Eminem spirit</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/the-eminem-spirit/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/the-eminem-spirit/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/the-eminem-spirit/img.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post The Eminem spirit" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been questioning my motivation. It feels like I have no reason to continue everything I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. I always feel sleepy. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t concentrate on my work, and my study, even though I was having my semester final exam. It was also the reason why I didn&amp;rsquo;t post anything on this blog for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, just when I find myself at the lowest, something comes back to me. Do you know what it is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening to Eminem&amp;rsquo;s music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I found out about his music. It was 6 years ago, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not Afraid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was immediately drawn to his lyrics and flows. At that time I didn&amp;rsquo;t know rap or hip hop, but I think he was speaking some emotional, inspiring thing that a student - in a teenage year like me - really needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, when you were 14 - 15, you started to grow older, and have your thoughts about life. You have some weird illusion about yourself and think that no one can understand you. My mom calls that age &amp;ldquo;the stupidest time in a human&amp;rsquo;s life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t have many friends back then. My day would only be like this: wake up, go to school, study, go home, games, sleep, and so on. Meanwhile, kids my age would hang out with each other all the time, eat out, go to the movies, etc. Basically I was a nerd, so my friends don&amp;rsquo;t want to play with me. You need to be &amp;ldquo;cool&amp;rdquo; to play with many people at secondary school, you know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, everything&amp;rsquo;s changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yeah&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a ride&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I guess I had to go to that place&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To get to this one&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now some of you might still be in that place&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re tryna get out&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just follow me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll get you there&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are the beginning lines of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not Afraid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.
Goosebumps, huh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His music has taught me so many things in life. I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to build trust in myself, overcome my shyness, always stand tall, and not give up. The day I took my high school entrance exam, I listened to Lose Yourself right before I entered the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music can make a different impact on each person. Although his music was controversial, I find it relatable and use his lyrics as my energy whenever I&amp;rsquo;m down for mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got into college, I listened to his music less. Partially because I got busier, but also because I got attracted to many other things. Trust me, when you&amp;rsquo;re in your 20s, it&amp;rsquo;s hard not to be attracted to some crazy things youth this age can do. Here are a few examples: spending money on unhealthy food, trips, clothes, etc. Of course not everything&amp;rsquo;s bad, but when people started to look at you differently, you have more things to concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence my GPA dropped. It&amp;rsquo;s not that bad, but it&amp;rsquo;s not what I expected at the beginning of this semester. I know I can achieve more, but I was so lazy and eventually got what I deserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i0EA3ur5mj4&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Stupid Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is my video that I make subtitles for one of Eminem&amp;rsquo;s songs. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I even made it but thank God, I feel like that same old energy was coming back to me. Just like 6 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Eminem spirit - not giving up, not giving a fuck about shit, only focus on what matters to you the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a long-lost spirit. Hope it&amp;rsquo;ll stay for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A day at Fville!</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/fpt.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A day at Fville!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got a chance to visit Fville - an FPT Software campus - yesterday. It was an amazing trip, with many exciting experiences and provoking thoughts for me. Before talking about what I think, let&amp;rsquo;s revisit the campus with me, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-experiences&#34;&gt;My experiences
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The journey began at 12:10 pm. We got picked up by a bus at our school library and head our way straight to Hoa Lac Hi-tech Park, which is about 40km far from my university (you can see the direction below). It took us 50 minutes to get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/map.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/map_hu4191623513522416740.png 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/map_hu16991177572093314178.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know, FPT Software is part of the FPT Corporation - one of the largest groups in Vietnam. This trip was held for students in HUST (like me) to see the chance of internships and working at FPT Software. Fville is one of FPT Software&amp;rsquo;s campuses, a space where its employees work together and enjoy all the facilities that suit their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, back to the story! When we arrived at the Fville, I was stunned by the view of the space. Fville has a modern design and is surrounded by &amp;ldquo;green&amp;rdquo; elements - trees, lakes, and grass paths. They even built a dam around the whole site to bring cool air into the buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/img.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2560&#34;
	height=&#34;1920&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/img_hu14853758836190081162.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/img_hu10741985886582225782.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;View from the lobby&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They give names for each floor and part of each floor following the name of streets in Hanoi. If I remember right, the first floor is called &amp;ldquo;Future&amp;rdquo;, with Ba Dinh &amp;amp; Hoan Kiem districts (2 districts of Hanoi), and each room will be named after a street or a lake. They have a map that includes everything about the area, but I forgot to take picture of that (my bad).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went into a big hall, called &amp;ldquo;Chu Sau&amp;rdquo; (Uncle Six?). They welcomed us with a small presentation about FPT, its history, and the corporate culture. After that, we played a small Kahoot about everything we just listened to, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t win it (I hate Kahoot). Next, they split us into groups to play a small game. The game required each team to solve a passcode. Our team solved the passcode shortly, and we found out our objective was to take a picture at the reception desk - which they use to upload on their FB fan page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the game is over, we could finally start to visit the building. Our tour guide was an FPT TA (talent acquisition) and an undergraduate student of FPT University. They were both kind, friendly, and energetic (also pretty :&amp;gt;). We got to see the facilities of Fville: gym, billiard, canteen, pool, working space (looks like they come here just to chill &amp;hellip;). They even have a motel that their employee can hire with a maximum of five people/ room for only 100k VND (which means less than a cup of coffee for each?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/lake.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2568&#34;
	height=&#34;1926&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/lake_hu543771999105064678.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/lake_hu6796744678804331068.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;My team in the middle of the lake&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/cuder.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2568&#34;
	height=&#34;1926&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/cuder_hu16333534971581016196.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/cuder_hu8766553038437069847.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;With the CUDER statue&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I like is that they have buses to pick their employees to work and give them catering services, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about how to get there, or buying food on the way home. It&amp;rsquo;s super convenient!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then return to the hall (&amp;ldquo;Chu Sau&amp;rdquo;) to play some team-building games. Our team got 4th out of 6 teams, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, because we had a wonderful time together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/final.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2493&#34;
	height=&#34;1869&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/final_hu15535054423945946303.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-day-at-fville/final_hu8569683201191455674.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;After the bonding game&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-thoughts&#34;&gt;My thoughts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After spending the afternoon there, having the chance to meet new people and see new things, I think I have learned so many things. Despite being a second-year student, I still struggle to find my path for my career, whether to become a developer to work in software or blockchains, or becoming an IoT engineer, or work at low-code positions like BA, QA, QC, DevOps, or maybe even work in HR, I still don&amp;rsquo;t know. But after the trip, I think I got my answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just do your thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, just do your thing. Focus on it and let it guide you. Many of the employees I met yesterday didn&amp;rsquo;t take the job that they learned at the university, but they all seemed happy with their job (at least that&amp;rsquo;s what I thought).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I mean is, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry that much about what to do in the future. If you have something that you&amp;rsquo;ve already worked on, keep doing it, and be good at it. That thing will lead you to opportunities that you might never think about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust me, I&amp;rsquo;m speaking from my own experience. Last year I held a &lt;strong&gt;TEDx Conference&lt;/strong&gt; - many ITers considered that a waste of time - but that experience has taught me so many things, and offer me the chance to work and make connections with people, which brought opportunities for me later on. My tour guide at FPT studied at &lt;strong&gt;FTU&lt;/strong&gt; (Foreign Trade University), a university that has nothing to do with technology, but many of her friends are working as Bridge Engineer and DevOps (which required knowledge in IT). And you know what they all have in common?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They ALL didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to do in their junior years, nor intended to do this job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of them got this position because they joined a club at university and worked on events, and one of them happened to be an event held by FPT. They took their chance to get their internship at FPT through that, and found out their exceptional skills would be suitable to be a DevOps. Do you get what I mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right people will come to you at the right time, just when you&amp;rsquo;re doing things you feel right. Don&amp;rsquo;t compare yourself to others, because you&amp;rsquo;ve already known:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re just doing their things.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Reminiscence</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/reminiscence/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/reminiscence/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/reminiscence/img.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Reminiscence" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A day can be special in many ways. So does the 9th of May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started at the beginning of 2018. The year that my life completely changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four years ago, someone stepped into my life. Someone used to be dreamy and mournful at the same time. Someone added laughter and tears to my daily days, emotions, and things that you could never forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone said yes on this day. Someone received a ring on this day, even though it didn&amp;rsquo;t fit at first. Someone tore me apart on this day, right before many decisive exams - I can still remember I was crying while doing that Toeic test. Someone came back, also on this day, after leaving for half a year, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t stay till the same day four years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where did we go wrong?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not someone&amp;rsquo;s fault, it&amp;rsquo;s just life separates us into different paths. You couldn&amp;rsquo;t chase after your dream and become a person I&amp;rsquo;ve never known. I achieved more than I can ever think of and become a person I&amp;rsquo;ve never expected. We both have gone so far from our path, increasing the distance between us. Do you think so?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if those years are enough for a lifetime. It&amp;rsquo;s stupid thinking so, but when I try to be in a new relationship or intend to, I just feel like trying to repeat everything in the past. Maybe I let others down, but what can I say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not trying to be nostalgic or missing someone. In the end, the memories stay, they might haunt you for days and nights, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got over that time. Now I can sit back and be calmful recalling everything, with a smile and pity on my face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey, what a love story that was!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ever come across this, just know that I cherish all the things we&amp;rsquo;ve been through. All the good and bad memories, all took part in making me who I am today. Maybe one day when everything is long gone, we&amp;rsquo;ll meet again, but as a different, grown person, with all the memories left behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whatever happened, you and I, we both deserve to be appreciated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Dawn Ahead</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/img.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Dawn Ahead" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s May. Summer is coming, with plenty of work ahead for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I have some projects to finish. One is from my club, which is to make some kinda blog website. One is from my class, in which I have to develop software to illustrate some sorting algorithms. Both are pretty challenging and even though I&amp;rsquo;ve been really familiar with such projects, they&amp;rsquo;ll still take me lots of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I&amp;rsquo;m competing in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creative Idea Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; at my university - a contest for students to present their startup ideas. If I can make it through the final round, I can present my idea in front of many people in English at the &lt;strong&gt;B1 lecture hall&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be a big day, and I really look forward to that, since that hall is incredibly cool, you can see it below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/hall.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1000&#34;
	height=&#34;667&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/hall_hu13877935389212698426.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/hall_hu3265428653450839009.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;149&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;359px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I&amp;rsquo;m having my mid-term exams at the end of the month,  just in time the above contest is over. This semester I&amp;rsquo;m studying &lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; subjects, which is an insane number (at least to me). But I&amp;rsquo;m not afraid. I will never give up once I&amp;rsquo;ve set the goals for myself, so let&amp;rsquo;s see how far I can go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny how terrible and stress I was last week and now I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get through everything. Today is labour day, and I think I can really sit back, chill out, enjoy the air of my countryside, as I can hardly have the chance to feel it once more the following month. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it peaceful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/sunset.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2559&#34;
	height=&#34;2560&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/sunset_hu5761924745262795251.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/sunset_hu8924083137063587004.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The title is dawn, but this picture is the sunset =))&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;99&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;239px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here.we.go!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Gloomy Sunday</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/gloomy-sunday/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/gloomy-sunday/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/gloomy-sunday/img.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Gloomy Sunday" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Sunday, the end of the week. Time to go out, refresh, and have yourself some rest after a long, tiring week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first month of my new semester has passed. I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to study quite hard this semester, and everything seems overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two homework this weekend, and both of them are from my coding classes. One is OOP, and the other one is the Programming Technique. Somehow I still haven&amp;rsquo;t finished both. It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating, especially when doubt starts to creep into your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many times have I wondered whether I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen the right major to study or not? I&amp;rsquo;m not a bad student at school, and I can proudly say I belong to the top ones. I know my strength compared to other students and the admiration I get from people. I know all of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why do I still feel so empty every Sunday?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People said I should be proud and satisfied with everything I&amp;rsquo;ve got. They think that I&amp;rsquo;m confident, sociable, and extremely good at my major. I even have a better income than most of the students my age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only if they knew how much I have sacrificed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned earlier, my two homework has caused me to doubt myself. It&amp;rsquo;s harmful to your mental health, especially when you&amp;rsquo;ve always tried so hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not intelligent. Not at all. Everything I&amp;rsquo;ve got was through trial and error. I hate when people say I&amp;rsquo;m smart, I&amp;rsquo;ll know how to resolve my own problem eventually. Or when they say I&amp;rsquo;m always confident and able to speak freely and get everyone&amp;rsquo;s attention. They don&amp;rsquo;t know my heart always beats like a drum while my body shakes every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why I always have an unconfident feeling whenever I tackle a difficult problem or situation. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I&amp;rsquo;m reaching my limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s even worse when there&amp;rsquo;s no one there for you to share your thoughts. I have friends, and many of them can really lend me an ear, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard for them to understand me thoroughly. They don&amp;rsquo;t know this side of me, partly because I hardly show it, partly because we&amp;rsquo;re basically not in the same league. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying this to dignify myself, but when you&amp;rsquo;re better than people, you&amp;rsquo;ll always feel lonely because they won&amp;rsquo;t ever know how to become someone like you, to feel the way you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, it will be just me and myself. I wish there could be someone else here, but that&amp;rsquo;s the price I have to pay. Maybe one day I&amp;rsquo;ll be rewarded. One day&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then, I still need to be strong. I might have a bad day like today, but I know I&amp;rsquo;ll come back stronger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get yourself up, as a new week is coming.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A Letter To Myself</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-letter-to-myself/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-letter-to-myself/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-letter-to-myself/img.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A Letter To Myself" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You wake up. Sun is shining, birds are singing, got yourself a hot coffee and you look outside the window to watch the sunrise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a wonderful start to the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, did you forget something? Today&amp;rsquo;s the final exam day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nah, you didn&amp;rsquo;t forget that. In fact, you knew it was coming, like, a month ago. Yeah, a month ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One month ago, you got all your exam schedules. You had prepared and listed out everything you need to do to prepare for all those exams, so no big deal! Everything would be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three weeks ago, your friend told you about a contest, which you found interesting. Or maybe you didn&amp;rsquo;t think it was that interesting, you just FOMO that you might lose the chance while everyone else didn&amp;rsquo;t. You spent a day just considering that, and in the end, you say no. But you lost a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, you were assigned a new task. It&amp;rsquo;s a new and challenging one since you&amp;rsquo;ve never worked on such projects before. At this time, you&amp;rsquo;ve finished some subjects&amp;rsquo; tests, and you had barely studied for the last one, the one that would come today. But still, that task was so intriguing, you decided to take that anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One week ago, you were still working on that project, at the same time studying for the final subject. You&amp;rsquo;re completely stressed out and exhausted. But more and more works kept on coming, just like Murphy&amp;rsquo;s law:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Anything that can go wrong will go wrong.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You started to feel hopeless. Three days to the exam, you had only studied half the subject.&lt;br&gt;
Two days to the exam, still no progress. One day to the exam&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiktok, tiktok. Time still ticking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day to the exam. You felt hopeless. How come everything always has to come at once?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s not something new these days. I mean, we all have plenty of work to do. Some we can control. Some we can&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hey, things still need to be done. It&amp;rsquo;s our responsibility to do that. We can&amp;rsquo;t control what&amp;rsquo;s coming to us, but we can control our emotions and act. How you face challenges, how you solve them, you&amp;rsquo;re the one who decides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to not be okay. But promise me, you&amp;rsquo;ll be strong afterward. Take a step back, like get some sleep, and return stronger than ever. Promise me you won&amp;rsquo;t give up, because you&amp;rsquo;ve tried so hard to go this far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better days will come, I promise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
